Before any team executes a complex play,
they ensure all the elements are in place.
We need to do the same for your 90-day plan.
This pre-game check isn't just about you.
It's about ensuring alignment
and two other critical areas,
your key relationships and your organization.
So let's start there.
We'll look at what's required for you personally,
but we'll also ask how does your plan align
with your team's goals and your organization's priorities?
And do you have the relational alignment
with your manager and stakeholders
and their expectations to make it happen?
Now, don't worry about whether you have
all these pieces in place.
Just think about what's required to succeed.
For this pre-game check,
we will look at the prerequisites in two key areas,
your personal readiness
and your relational organizational alignment.
First, personal readiness.
This is your internal state.
It includes your mindset,
the belief you can achieve your goals,
your motivation and your energy,
your specific skills, knowledge and credentials.
But that's only half of the picture.
The other half is your relational
and organizational alignment.
This is how you show up as a leader.
This includes your manager alignment,
peer collaboration, direct report relationships.
Having both your personal readiness
and your relational alignment in place
is what truly prepares you for the game.
Let me give you an example.
I worked with Lynn, an attorney reentering the workplace
and becoming lead in-house counsel.
Her success wasn't just about her personal skills.
It was about creating a 360 degree alignment.
First, she needed relational alignment at home,
getting on the same page with her spouse
and securing reliable childcare system
to help her in her new schedule.
Then she established manager alignment at work.
She and her new boss created a plan
with crystal clear priorities.
Finally, that clarity cascaded to her new team.
Guided by a shared purpose and mission,
they were all empowered to say no to low impact requests.
This protected their time and focused their energy,
driving incredible efficiency.
That is how alignment across your entire life
creates productivity that you need to handle
major moments of change.
Understanding all of these prerequisites
didn't discourage her.
It empowered her.
It gave her a clear checklist of what she needed to work on.
In your playbook, the first drill will guide you
through identifying the essential elements of success
for your own vision.
This is your pregame check.